Imagine for a moment you've travelled 2,000 years into the future.
想象一下，你穿越到了2000年后的未来。
Which human foods do you think would stand the test of time, and would any of it still be edible?
你认为哪些人类食物能够经受住时间的考验，其中哪些食物还可以被人类食用？
To find out, we first need to understand what makes food go off.
要找到答案，我们首先需要了解食物为什么会变质。
Food preservation's main opponent is microbial growth.
食物保存的主要敌人是微生物生长。
An expert in food chemistry, Michael Sulu, says most foods spoil for that reason.
食品化学专家迈克尔·苏鲁说，大多数食物变质都是因为这个原因。
When things like bacteria, mould and yeast grow on your food, it can become pathogenic, and food causing disease is best avoided!
当细菌、霉菌和酵母等微生物在食物上生长时，食物可能会致病，引起疾病的食物最好避免！
So, how can we limit their growth?
那么，我们该如何限制它们的生长呢？
Microbes love oxygen and water, so the key is to starve them of it.
微生物喜欢氧气和水，所以关键是要让它们缺乏这些。
We can do this by drying, salting, chilling, or storing the food in airtight containers.
我们可以通过干燥、盐腌、冷藏或将食物储存在密封容器中来做到这一点。
According to Sulu, drying is the most effective because without water, microbes can't multiply.
根据苏鲁的说法，干燥是最有效的方法，因为没有水，微生物就无法繁殖。
Freezing works in the short-term, but explorers who have found ancient frozen animals initially thought the meat looked edible, but once defrosted, it immediately became putrid, which doesn't sound at all palatable!
冷冻在短期内有效，但发现古代冰冻动物的探险家们最初认为肉看起来可以食用，但一旦解冻，肉会立即腐烂，这听起来一点也不可口！
But how can we make our favourite foods longer-lasting if we don't want to dry, salt or freeze them?
但如果我们不想干燥、盐腌或冷冻，如何让我们最喜欢的食物保存更久呢？
That's where additives and preservatives come in.
这就轮到添加剂和防腐剂发挥作用了。
These chemicals help to improve the shelf life of our supermarket items, but it means the food becomes ultra-processed.
这些化学物质有助于延长我们超市商品的保质期，但这意味着食物变成了超加工食品。
High consumption of ultra-processed food is linked to problems like depression and obesity, according to a review of the research by Pagliai and colleagues in the British Journal of Nutrition.
根据帕利亚伊及其同事在《英国营养学杂志》上的一项研究综述，抑郁和肥胖等问题与大量食用超加工食品有关。
So, what's going to be safe for us to eat in our hypothetical time travel scenario?
那么，在我们假想的时空旅行场景中，什么食物对我们来说是安全的呢？
"I would start off with anything that is vacuum-packed or dried as well," says Sulu.
苏鲁说："我会先从任何真空包装或干燥的食物开始。"
If you can't find any of that, you could go to the Global Seed Vault in Svalbard, Norway, where there are almost one million samples of seeds from all over the world.
如果找不到这些，你可以去挪威斯瓦尔巴的全球种子库，那里有来自世界各地的近一百万份种子样本。
They're in vaults designed to last forever, buried beneath the Arctic permafrost, so either eat the seeds, or start repopulating the plant world!
它们被存放在设计为可以永久保存的保险库中，埋藏在北极永久冻土层之下，所以要么吃掉这些种子，要么开始重新繁衍植物世界！